{"id":"2018_22","name":"","memoryVerse":"\"But you, Lord, are a shield around me, my glory, the One who lifts my head high.\" – Psalm 3:3","dayQuestions":{"one":{"title":"FIRST DAY: Read the notes and the references.","questions":[{"id":"2018_22_1","questionText":"1. Use this space to record how you have seen God's activity during the week. (How has He provided, answered, comforted, reconciled, guided, etc.?)","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_22_2","questionText":"2. What from the notes, lecture, group sharing or personal study impacted you most in the past week?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"two":{"title":"SECOND DAY: Read 2 Samuel 19-20.\nDavid faced challenging decisions as he returned to rule Israel as king.","readVerse":[{"book":"2 Samuel","verse":"19:1-20:999"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_22_3","questionText":"3. Describe David's reaction to Absalom's death. How do you assess Joab's advice to David?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_22_4","questionText":"4. Consider the friends and foes David encountered as he returned and settled in Jerusalem. What do you learn about David? What do you learn about David's view of God and others?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_22_5","questionText":"5. How does this passage encourage or embolden you in your present circumstances? How will you respond?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"three":{"title":"THIRD DAY: Read 2 Samuel 21-22.\nDavid sought God's wisdom, battled his enemies and celebrated God's kindness.","readVerse":[{"book":"2 Samuel","verse":"21:1-22:999"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_22_6","questionText":"6. What does David's encounter with the Gibeonites teach you about sin, restitution and God? (See Joshua 9:15.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Joshua","verse":"9:15"}]},{"id":"2018_22_7","questionText":"7. From 2 Samuel 22, what do the words and images say about David's relationship with and attitude toward God? What words describe God's kindness toward David?","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"2 Samuel","verse":"22:1-999"}]},{"id":"2018_22_8","questionText":"8. Which verses help, encourage or inspire you to worship? Why?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"four":{"title":"FOURTH DAY: Read 2 Samuel 23.\nDavid celebrated God's gracious provision and victory through his mighty men.","readVerse":[{"book":"2 Samuel","verse":"23:1-999"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_22_9","questionText":"9. What do David's last words reveal about his understanding of God's work in his life?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_22_10","questionText":"10. How did David's men show bravery and loyalty to him? How will you demonstrate sacrificial love and loyalty at work, church and/or in your home?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_22_11","questionText":"11. In 2 Samuel 22, David credits God for his victories. How do you reconcile the heroic acts of David's mighty men with 2 Samuel 22? What do these two chapters teach you about the victorious Christian life?","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"2 Samuel","verse":"22:1-999"},{"book":"2 Samuel","verse":"22:1-999"}]}]},"five":{"title":"FIFTH DAY: Read 2 Samuel 24 with 1 Chronicles 21.\nDavid's census resulted in a deadly plague and costly sacrifice.","readVerse":[{"book":"2 Samuel","verse":"24:1-999"},{"book":"1 Chronicles","verse":"21:1-999"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_22_12","questionText":"12. How might David have sinned in taking the census? (Use Exodus 30:12; James 1:13-16 or any other Scripture reference.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Exodus","verse":"30:12"},{"book":"James","verse":"1:13-16"}]},{"id":"2018_22_13","questionText":"13. What do you learn about God's judgment and mercy in response to the census? How have you experienced God's judgment and mercy?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_22_14","questionText":"14. How did David demonstrate reverence for God? How do you see God's people demonstrating reverence to God in your culture?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"six":{"title":"SIXTH DAY: Review 2 Samuel 19-24.","readVerse":[{"book":"2 Samuel","verse":"19:1-24:999"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_22_15","questionText":"15. How did this week's study week impact your thinking about unity – within your family, church, community or nation?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]}}}